David is 11 years old. He weighs 60 pounds. He is 4 feet, 6 inches
tall. He has brown hair. His love is real. But he is not.
A.I. Artificial Intelligence is a drama, science fiction,
adventure film directed by Steven Spielberg.
David, a robotic boy—the first of his kind programmed to love—is adopted
as a test case by a Cybertronics employee and his wife.
Though he gradually becomes their child, a series of unexpected
circumstances make this life impossible for David.
David, played by Haley Joel Osment.
Gigolo Joe, played by Jude Law.
Monica Swinton, played by Frances O'Connor.
Henry Swinton, played by Sam Robards.
Martin Swinton, played by Jake Thomas.
Prof. Hobby, played by William Hurt.
Artificial Intelligence (or simply A.I.) is a 2001 science
fiction drama film directed by Steven Spielberg.
The screenplay by Spielberg and screen story by Ian Watson are loosely based on the
1969 short story "Supertoys Last All Summer Long" by Brian Aldiss.
Set in a futuristic society, the film stars Haley Joel Osment as David, a
childlike android uniquely programmed with the ability to love.
Jude Law, Frances O'Connor, Brendan Gleeson and
William Hurt star in supporting roles.
Development of A.I.
originally began after producer and director Stanley Kubrick
acquired the rights to Aldiss's story in the early 1970s.
Kubrick hired a series of writers, including Aldiss, Bob Shaw,
Ian Watson and Sara Maitland, until the mid-1990s.
The film languished in development hell for years, partly because Kubrick felt that computer-generated imagery was not
advanced enough to create the David character, which he believed no child actor would convincingly portray.
In 1995, Kubrick handed A.I.
to Spielberg, but the film did not gain momentum until Kubrick died in 1999.
Spielberg remained close to Watson's treatment for the
screenplay and dedicated the film to Kubrick.
Artificial Intelligence was released on June 29, 2001, by Warner Bros.
It received generally positive reviews from critics and grossed
$235.9 million against a budget of $90–100 million.
It was also nominated for Best Visual Effects and Best Original
Score (for John Williams) at the 74th Academy Awards.
In a 2016 BBC poll of 177 critics around the world, A.I.
Artificial Intelligence was voted the eighty-third greatest film since 2000.
It has since been called one of Spielberg's best works and one of the
greatest films of the 21st century, and of all time.
The film explores themes of android, prostitute, artificial
intelligence (a.i.), prophecy, loss of loved one.
The tone is emotional and thought_provoking.